# Jermaine Smith

### **Wordpress and Front-End Developer**

Romeoville, IL 60446 jermainesmittysr@gmail.com +1 7737072652

Experienced developer / designer with a versatile technical skill set currently seeking mid-level to senior role or contract opportunities. In the past 6+ years, I've completed or managed 80+ websites while greatly expanding my knowledge and skillset through contract work and freelancing. I take pride in exceeding expectations and bringing tremendous value to any organization I work with.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

### Work Experience

### **Director of Web Development**

Veritas Group - Austin, TX December 2020 to Present

- Evaluating new technologies to improve organizational operations
- Create a digital strategy for implementing new technical solutions
- Analyzing data for developing solutions to problems
- · Coordinating with marketing/PR teams to create and promote new content for websites
- Managing website operations including hosting, maintenance, and security

### **Contract Web Developer**

Blueprint Design & Media - Chicago, IL May 2019 to Present

- Consult clients on business needs including web development and digital marketing.
- Propose marketing, design, and development solutions based on needs assessment
- Design customer websites and digital media assets as needed
- Develop websites using Wordpress, Shopify, and Front-End Technologies including HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Update and maintain client websites and assets as needed
- Develop and execute marketing strategy including: digital advertising, SEO, funnel development, growth hacking, etc.

#### **Wordpress & Shopify Developer**

Dream Bigger Media Group - Miami, FL January 2018 to May 2019

- Consulted clients on technical needs
- Recommended technical solutions based on needs assessment
- Collaborated with web design team with PSD design to development workflow
- Developed client websites using Wordpress, Shopify, and Front-End Technologies
- Created content and digital media as needed
- · Maintained and updated websites as necessary

### **Junior Wordpress Developer**

Songsplits - New York, NY March 2016 to January 2018

- Assisted with the development and maintenance of WordPress site
- Created content and maintained social media post scheduling
- · Executed data scraping and wrangling tasks using various tools and python scripts

### Education

### **Bachelor's in Business Administration**

DeVry University-Chicago - Tinley Park, IL August 2007 to June 2009

#### **Business Administration**

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS URBANA - Champaign, IL August 2002 to June 2004

### High school or equivalent

Joliet West High School - Joliet, IL August 1998 to June 2002

### Skills

- CSS3
- Wordpress
- Shopify
- Javascript
- Photoshop
- Sketch
- Bootstrap
- Front End
- HTML5
- Facebook Advertising
- SEO
- GitHub
- PHP
- Graphic Design
- Analysis Skills
- Web Development
- Web Design
- React
- APIs
- Final Cut Pro

- REST
- Responsive web design
- DNS
- Website maintenance
- User Experience (UX)
- User Interface (UI)
- Gatsby
- Figma
- Adobe Premiere
- Wireframing
- Visual design
- SCSS
- SQL
- Web accessibility
- Back-end development
- Full-stack development
- MySQL
- Google Analytics
- WCAG
- JSON
- jQuery
- NextJS (1 year)
- Tailwind CSS (1 year)
- Adobe InDesign
- Jira
- XML

### Links

https://jermainesmithsr.github.io/

### Assessments

# **Logic & Critical Thinking — Expert**

September 2019

Using logic to solve problems.

Full results: Expert

## **Attention to Detail — Expert**

September 2019

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: Expert

### **Problem Solving — Expert**

September 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to analyze relevant information when solving problems

Full results: Expert

### **Data Analysis** — **Expert**

September 2019

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data.

Full results: Expert

### Composing & Sorting Email — Expert

September 2019

Effectively composing and organizing email messages.

Full results: Expert

### **Social Media — Expert**

September 2019

Creating content, communicating online, and building a brand's reputation.

Full results: Expert

## **Research** — **Proficient**

September 2019

Following protocols, interpreting statistics and graphs, identifying errors, and choosing research methodology.

Full results: Proficient

### Search Engine Optimization — Highly Proficient

January 2020

 $Interpreting\ online\ website\ performance\ metrics\ and\ understanding\ search\ engine\ optimization\ tactics$ 

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Expert

January 2020

Excel knowledge including common tools, PivotTables, conditional & nested formulas, and custom visuals.

Full results: Expert

#### Written Communication — Proficient

March 2020

Best practices for writing, including grammar, style, clarity, and brevity.

Full results: Proficient

### Logic & critical thinking — Expert

September 2019

Using logic to solve problems.

Full results: Expert

# **Search engine optimization — Highly Proficient**

January 2020

Interpreting online website performance metrics and understanding search engine optimization tactics Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.